Guide to the Jacques Barzun Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: 1976 Gift
  - The American University--Reports on Columbia University Administration (Box 31, Folder 48)
  - The American University--Reports on Columbia University Administration-printing (Box 31, Folder 48)
  - The American University--Notes & materials-by chapters (Box 31, Folder 49)
  - The American University--Columbia Univrsity facts & statistics (Box 31, Folder 49)
  - The American University--General reference (Box 32, Folder 49)
  - The American University--Tables, figures, money matters (Box 32, Folder 50)
  - The American University--Computers (Box 32, Folder 50)
  - The American University--Tables, etc.-money (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - The American University -- Classified items: universities at large (Box 33, Folder 51)
  - The American University--Administration (Box 33, Folder 51)
  - The American University--Student troubles: world-wide (Box 34, Folder 52)
  - The American University--Curriculum and objections. (Box 34, Folder 53)
  - The American University--More student protest (Box 36, Folder 54)
  - The American University-- Reports on Columbia University (Box 36, Folder 54)
  - The American University--Reports on administration (Box 36, Folder 56)
  - The American University -- Clippings, magazines, etc. to January 1969 (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - The American University -- Extra material file (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Science: The Glorious Entertainment -- I: The teaching of science and mathematics--Clippings, reports, etc. (Box 38, Folder 57)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment. -- II: The social sciences. Clippings, reports, etc. (Box 39, Folder 58)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment. -- Editorial notes (Box 39, Folder 56)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment. -- Notes from readings (Box 39, Folder 58)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment -- III: Science in world affairs. Clippings, reports, etc. (Box 40, Folder 59)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment-- Chapters I --III: Clippings, etc. (Box 41, Folder 60)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment-- Chapters I -- VIII: Clippings, etc. (Box 42, Folder 61)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment-- Chapters IX -- XIII: Clippings, etc. (Box 43, Folder 62)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment -- Possible new insertions in manuscript (Box 43, Folder 62)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment -- Dates & other references to existing footnotes (Box 43, Folder 62)
  - Science: the Glorious Entertainment -- Correspondence, January 1960-December 1964 (Box 43, Folder 71)
  - The American University. Reports & speeches; news releases (Box 44, Folder 61a)
  - The American University. Reports & speeches; news releases (Box 44, Folder 62a)
  - The American University. Reports & speeches; news releases (Box 45, Folder 62a)
  - The American University. Reports & opinions (Box 45, Folder 63)
  - The American University. Professional salaries (Box 45, Folder 63)
  - The American University. Money matters (Box 46, Folder 64)
  - The American University. Planning and fund raising (Box 47, Folder 65)
  - Report to the Trustees’ Committee about workload & salaries (Box 47, Folder 63)
  - The Mid-Century Century Book Society:
    - Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 25, Folder 39-40)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Advertisements, 1959-1963 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Contracts, correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Facts & figures, 1959-1963 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Financial reports, 1959-1962 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, June 1959-June 1962 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, July 1960-December 1963 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Articles -- comments. Correspondence, January 196l-June 1962 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January -December 1961 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Personal invitations, September 1958-December 1962 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Personal correspondence, July 1960.December 1962 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January 1962.December 1963 (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January 1962-December 1963 (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Lectures--comments. Correspondence, July 1960-December 1964 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Critic--general. Correspondence, July 1961-June 1965 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January -December 1964 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January -December 1964 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, /010/1963-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, /010/l963-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Articles--comments. Correspondence, July 1962-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, July 1962-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, January 1964.-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - The American University:
    - Reports on Columbia University Administration (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - Reports on Columbia University Administration--printing (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - Notes & materials--by chapters (Box 31, Folder 49)
    - Columbia University facts & statistics (Box 31, Folder 49)
    - General reference (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Tables, figures, money matters (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Computers (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Tables, etc.--money (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - Classified items: universities at large (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - Administration (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - Student troubles world-wide (Box 34, Folder 52)
    - Curriculum and objections (Box 35, Folder 53)
    - More student protests (Box 36, Folder 54)
    - Reports on Columbia Univesity (Box 36, Folder 54)
    - Reports on administration (Box 36, Folder 56)
    - Clippings, magazines, etc. to January 1969 (Box 37, Folder 55)
    - Extra material file (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Science the Glorious Entertainment:
    - I. The teaching of science and mathematics. Clippings, reports, etc. (Box 38, Folder 57)
    - II. The social sciences. Clippings, reports, etc. (Box 39, Folder 58)
    - Editorial notes (Box 39, Folder 56)
    - Notes from readings (Box 39, Folder 56)
    - III. Science in world affairs. Clippings, reports, etc. (Box 40, Folder 59)
    - Chapters I-III. Clippings, etc. (Box 41, Folder 60)
    - Chapters I-VIII. Clippings, etc. (Box 42, Folder 61)
    - Chapters IX-XIII. Clippings, etc. (Box 43, Folder 62)
    - Possible new insertions in manuscript (Box 43, Folder 62)
    - Dates and other references to existing footnotes (Box 43, Folder 62)
    - Correspondence, January l96O-December l964 (Box 43, Folder 71)
  - The American University:
    - Reports & speeches; news releases (Box 44, Folder 61a)
    - Reports & speeches; news releases (Box 44, Folder 62a)
    - Reports & speeches; news releases (Box 45, Folder 62a)
    - Reports &: opinions (Box 45, Folder 63)
    - Professional salaries (Box 45, Folder 63)
    - Money matters (Box 46, Folder 64)
    - Planning & fund raising (Box 47, Folder 65)
  - Report to the Trustees’ Committee about workload & salaries (Box 47, Folder 63)
  - The American University:The Provost’s office (Box 48, Folder 66)
  - Race: A Modern Superstition -- documents, clippings, etc. (Box 48, Folder 67)
  - Romanticism and the Modern Ego -- documents and clippings (Box 48, Folder 67)
  - God's Country and Mine:
    - documents, clippings (arranged by chapters) (Box 49, Folder 68)
    - documents, clippings (arranged by chapters) (Box 50, Folder 68)
    - documents, clippings (unsorted) (Box 50, Folder 69)
  - The Modern Researcher: Correspondence, April 1954-December 1959 (Box 51, Folder 70)
  - The House of Intellect: Correspondence, January 1960-December 1964 (Box 51, Folder 71)
  - Permissions -- Correspondence, 1946-December 1963 (Box 52, Folder 72)
  - Critic--advertising. Correspondence, Janury 1961-December 1968 (Box 52, Folder 73)
  - Critic -- members & sponsors. Correspondence, September 1961-December 1966 (Box 52, Folder 73)
  - Critic ---appeals. Correspondence, July 1962-December 1966 (Box 53, Folder 73)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January 1965-July 1966 (Box 53, Folder 74)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January 1965-July 1966 (Box 53, Folder 74)
  - The American University:
    - Supplementary material after publication (Box 54, Folder 75)
    - Supplementary material to August 1969 & University essay (Box 55, Folder 76)
    - Supplementary material (Box 56, Folder 77)
    - Supplementary material after publication (Box 57, Folder 78)
    - Supplementary material after publication (Box 58, Folder 79)
    - Supplementary material after publication (Box 59, Folder 80)
  - The Energies of Art (1956). Manuscript notes & clippings (Box 60, Folder 81)
  - Lectures--comments. Correspondence, January 1965-December 1968 (Box 61, Folder 82)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, July 1966-December 1968 (Box 61, Folder 82)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, August 1966-December 1968 (Box 61, Folder 82)
  - Lectures--comments. Correspondence, Jan,-December 1969 (Box 62, Folder 83)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January -December 1969 (Box 62, Folder 83)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, Jan, December 1969 (Box 62, Folder 83)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, January 1966-December 1969 (Box 62, Folder 84)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, January 1966-December 1969 (Box 62, Folder 84)
  - Articles--comment. Correspondence, January 1966-December 1969 (Box 63, Folder 85)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, January 1966-December 1969 (Box 63, Folder 85)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, January 1966-December 1969 (Box 63, Folder 85)
  - The American University. Correspondence, June 1961-December 1969 (Box 63, Folder 86)
  - Century Club Association. Correspondence, January 1969-December 1970 (Box 64, Folder 87)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, April 1964-September 1971 (Box 64, Folder 87)
  - Personal invitations, January l963-June 1969 (Box 64, Folder 88)
  - The American Scholar. Correspondence, January 190l-December 1969 (Box 65, Folder 89)
  - Permissions. Correspondence, January 1964-December 1969 (Box 65, Folder 90)
  - Detective fiction (subject). Correspondence, 1938-December 1970 (Box 66, Folder 91)
  - The Delights of Detection:
    - Correspondence about permissions, 1960-1961 (Box 66, Folder 91)
    - Correspondence, January 1960-December 1969 (Box 66, Folder 91)
    - Notes, etc., 1960 (Box 66, Folder 91)
  - Catalogue of Crime:
    - Correspondence, September 1968-December 1970 (Box 66, Folder 91)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 66, Folder 91)
  - Critic--general. Correspondence, June 1965-December 197l (Box 67, Folder 92)
  - Articles--comments. Correspondence, January 1970-December 1971 (Box 67, Folder 92)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, January l970-December l971 (Box 67, Folder 92)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, January 1970-December 1971 (Box 67, Folder 92)
  - Critic-advising. Correspondence, January 1967-December 1971 (Box 68, Folder 93)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, January 1970-December 1971 (Box 68, Folder 93)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, January 1970-December 1971 (Box 68, Folder 93)
  - Lectures--comments. Correspondence, January l970-December 1971 (Box 68, Folder 94)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January l97O-December 1971 (Box 68, Folder 94)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January 1970-December 1971 (Box 69, Folder 94)
  - Lectures--comments. Correspondence, January 1972-December 1972 (Box 69, Folder 94)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January 1972-December 1972 (Box 69, Folder 94)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January 1972-December 1972 (Box 69, Folder 94)
  - Opinions to author. Correspondence, January 1972-December 1973 (Box 69, Folder 95)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, January 1972·December 1973 (Box 69, Folder 95)
  - Crcwe11, Collier, Macmillan, Inc. Minutes & reports, June 1966-December 1970 (Box 70, Folder 96)
  - Crowell, Collier, Macmillan, Inc. Correspondence, etc. January 1965-December 1971 (Box 70, Folder 97)
  - Macmillan, Inc. (Crowell, Collier, Macmillan, Inc.). Correspondence, reports, etc., January l972-December 1973 (Box 71, Folder 98)
  - Macmillan Education Committee, 1965-1968 (Box 71, Folder 98)
  - 1170 Fifth Avenue Corporation, November 1959-December 1968 (Box 71, Folder 99)
  - Official statements and directives on academic matters, /010/l955-June 1967 (Box 72, Folder 100)
  - Life magazine -- "History of Western Man". Correspondence, etc., 1947-1952 (Box 72, Folder 100)
  - Life magazine -- "History of Western Man". Typescript, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 100)
  - Perspectives III (magazine). Correspondence, etc., 1952-1953 (Box 73)
  - The Selected Letters of Lord Byron. Correspondence, 1952-1954-1972 (Box 73)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, June 1954-August 1955 (Box 73)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, June 1954-August 1955 (Box 73)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, July 1954-September 1955 (Box 73)
  - American Bookshelf project (Carnegie Corp.) Correspondence, etc. 1956-1958 (Box 74)
  - American Bookshelf project. Lists, 1956 (Box 74)
  - American Bookshelf project. Promotion, 1957-1958 (Box 74)
  - Humanistic Institute (proposed institute for the study of man--Ruth Nanda Ashen, May 1957-July 1958 (Box 74)
  - Music. Correspondence with musicians, 1931-1952 (Box 75)
  - Music. Correspondence with Cecil Hopkinson, 1939-1952 (Box 75)
  - Pleasures of Music (New York & London). Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 75)
  - Music. General correspondence, July 1953-August 1955 (Box 75)
  - Gifts to the Columbia University Libraries, 1952-1970 (Box 75)
  - The Modern Researcher. Notes & clippings, 1961-1969 (Box 76)
  - Correspondence with Warner H. Mendel about tax and business affairs, 1936-1967 (Box 77 & 78)
  - Congressional Committee on Drug Abuse. Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 79)
  - Early manuscripts and correspondence:
    - Tutoring, etc. Correspondence & accounts, 1924-1932 (Box 80)
    - "Ghosts, Incorporated"--translations & ghostwriting, 1925-1930 (Box 80)
    - Columbia Varsity-Spectator-Philolexian-etc. 1926-1937 (Box 80)
    - Zuleika (C.U. Varsity show), 1927 (Box 80)
    - Hackwork--Longmans Green, Colliers Encyclopedia, Keller’s Digest of Books, Carnegie Foundation, 1928-1946 (Box 80)
    - Book reviews by J.B., 1930s & 1940s (Box 80)
  - Sarah Lawrence College & Briarcliff Junior College. Correspondence, etc., 1935-l943 (Box 80)
  - "The writings of Henry Wilson". Six volumes, typescript (Box 81)
  - Follett's Modern American Usage:
    - Galley proofs (Box 82)
    - Manuscript drafts (Box 83)
    - Xerox copy of typescript with Barzun’s notes (Box 84)
    - Xerox copy as submitted to co-editor (Box 85)
    - Copy edited typescript (Box 86)
    - Index on cards (Box 87)
    - Page proofs & galley proofs (Box 89)
    - Page proofs, foundry proofs & misc. (Box 90)
    - Page proofs (Box 91)
    - Edited typescript (Box 92)
  - Mrs. Barzun & misc. (& Guy Lowell obits., 1927), 1935-1949 (Box 93)
  - Boston Athenaeum, 1939-1945 (Box 93)
  - Civil defense, 1942-1945 (Box 93)
  - The Dalton School, 1944-1955 (Box 93)
  - Gray, Cleve -- JB’s portrait & F.E. Lowell watercolor, 1948-1951 (Box 93)
  - M.I.T. -- Visiting Committee, 1949-1955 (Box 93)
  - Personal correspondence, invitations, clippings, memorabilia, 1932-1962 (Box 93)
  - Columbia University:
    - Correspondence, clippings, misc., 1953-1949 (Box 95)
    - Bicentennial, 1952-June 1954 (Box 95)
    - Bicentennial conference, 1954-1955 (Box 95)
    - Bicentennial editions and studies, 1954-1955 (Box 95)
    - Bicentennial histories, 1954-1955 (Box 95)
    - Business affairs, 1954-1955 (Box 95)
    - Convocation speech, 1947-1948 (Box 95)
    - Graduate record Examination, 1938-1945 (Box 95)
    - History Department, 1936-1950 (Box 96)
    - History Department, 1949-1955 (Box 97)
    - History Department -- Colloquium 3-4 (Box 97)
    - History Department -- Naval history (Hist. N-3), 1943-1944 (Box 97)
    - Humanities -- Conferences, lectures, etc., 1944-1951 (Box 98)
    - Humanities -- "Invitation to learning" (WMCA), UNESCO, articles, etc., 1935-1949 (Box 98)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1940-1954 (Box 99)
    - Political Science, Faculty of -- Secretary, 1946-1951 (Box 99)
    - Printed periodicals, 1903-1948 (Box 99)
    - Recommendations: A-Z, 1927-1945 (Box 99)
    - Students: A-J. Correspondence, 1935-1953 (Box 100)
    - Students: K-Z. Correspondence, 1942-1945 (Box 101)
    - Student Auxiliary Corp. -- First aid, 1942-1945 (Box 101)
    - University committees (Steeves, Putnam, Bicentennial, Columbia College, University Council, History of Science, Columbia Press, other), 1946-1948 (Box 102)
    - University committees (Bicentennial, Columbia Press, other), 1949-1951 (Box 102)
    - University committees (Putnam, Bicentennial, Columbia College Development, other), 1952-1954 (Box 102)
  - Letters: friends-Wendell H. Taylor (Restricted), 1925-1933 (Box 103)
  - Letters: friends-Wendell H. Taylor (Restricted), 1934-1945 (Box 104)
  - Letters: friends-Wendell H. Taylor (Restricted), 1946-1956 (Box 105)
  - Letters: friends-Wendell H. Taylor (Restricted), 1957-62; 1963-67 (Box 105 a&b)
  - Letters: friends-Wendell H. Taylor (Restricted), 1968-1973 (continues in Box 238) (Box 106)
  - Letters: friends-Louise Hetig Taylor, 1935-1940 (Box 106)
  - Letters: friends-Tom S. Wotton (Restricted) (Box 107)
  - Letters:. friends, 1925-1943 (Box 108)
  - Letters: friends, 1944-1949 (Box 109)
  - Letters: friends, 1950-1960 (Box 110)
  - Letters: friends, 1960-1972 (Box 111)
  - Personal--contributions, 1962-1971 (Box 112)
  - Personal correspondence, & (booksellers, 1957-1963), 1962-1972 (Box 112)
  - Personal invitations, 1969-1974 (Box 112)
  - Inscriptions, 1969-1974 (Box 112)
  - Correspondence with friends: A-F (Box 113)
  - Correspondence with friends: G-M (Box 114)
  - Correspondence with friends: N-Z (Box 115)
  - Romanticism and the Modern Ego. Correspondence, 1932-1961 (Box 116)
  - Of Human Freedom. Correspondence, 1936-1972 (Box 116)
  - Columbia University:
    - Advisory Council: Art History, etc., 1963-1973 (Box 117)
    - (Adviser on the arts) Arts Center (fund-raising & building), 1962-1972 (Box 117)
    - Brooklyn Museum and Art History Dept., 1969 (Box 117)
    - Committee on art properties, 1963-1975 (Box 117)
    - Committee on the School of the Arts, 1970-1974 (Box 117)
    - Cultural events, 1967-19745 (Box 118)
    - (Adviser on the arts)Electronic music, 1963-1967 (Box 118)
    - Faculty of the Arts, 1967-1974 (Box 118)
    - General, 1963-1974 (Box 118)
    - Ph.D. in Theater program Committee, 1967-1973 (Box 118)
    - University Committee on Artistic Events, 1969-1970 (Box 118)
    - Writing program -- School of the Arts, 1964-1974 (Box 118)
    - University Professorship:
      - Consultations, 1968-1975 (Box 119)
      - Faculty matters, 1967-1975 (Box 119)
      - Forum publication committee, 1971-1975 (Box 119)
      - General matters, 1969-1975 (Box 120)
      - John Jay Scholarship Program, 1967-1971 (Box 120)
      - Memoranda to the Vice President, 1967 (Box 120)
      - Office matters, 1967-1975 (Box 120)
      - Official and personal re1ations, 1966-1972 (Box 120)
      - Public Interest Meetings, 1969 (Box 120)
      - Reid Hall, 1967-1975 (Box 120)
      - "Restructuring" C.U., 1968-1971 (Box 121)
      - Student matters, 1967-1975 (Box 121)
      - The "Unity of Knowledge" group, 1967-1968 (Box 121)
      - University matters -- Administration & policies, 1967-1975 (Box 121)
      - University matters -- General information & notices, 1967-1975 (Box 122)
      - University seminar on the Romantic Movement, 1971-1972 (Box 122)
      - University Senate, 1969-1971 (Box 122)
    - Dissertations, A-Z, 1953-1973 (Box 122)
    - Students, A-Z, 1967-1975 (Box 123)
    - History Department:
      - History Department, 1960-1975 (Box 124)
      - Examinations -- misc. (Box 124)
      - Language examinations, 1948-1955 (Box 124)
      - Reading lists -- European History (Box 125)
      - Reading lists -- J.B. (Box 125)
      - Reading lists -- others (Box 125)
      - Seminar, 1953-1973 (Box 125)
      - Seminar -- reading lists (Box 125)
      - Students, 1962-1975 (Box 126)
      - 139-140 (Box 126)
      - 139-140 (examinations) (Box 126)
      - 201 -- Correspondence, 1950-1963 (Box 126)
      - 201 -- Outlines, etc. (Box 126)
      - 201 -- Notes (Box 126)
      - 4166y -- lecture course, 1969-1973 (Box 127)
      - 4166y -- lecture course (examinations) (Box 127)
      - 4166y -- lecture course (roster & grades), 1969 (Box 127)
      - 8230-8231 -- colloquium, 1972-1975 (Box 127)
      - Report of the Committee on Scholarly Publications, 1956 (Box 127)
      - University Seminar on Higher Education, 1950-1953 (Box 127)
      - Friends of the Columbia Libraries, 1968-1972 (Box 127)
  - Arts and Letters:
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1954-1970 (Box 128)
    - American Committee on Cultural Freedom (Box 128)
    - The American Freedom Traim Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 128)
    - Center for the Study of Education, 1969 (Box 128)
    - The Century Association, 1969-1971 (Box 128)
    - Council for Basic Education, 1966-1972 (Box 128)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1972-1975 (Box 128)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1959-1968 (Box 128)
    - The English-Speaking Union, 1965 (Box 129)
    - France-America Society, 1958-1962 (Box 129)
    - The Little Orchestra Society, Inc., 1965-1973 (Box 129)
    - The National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1961-1971 (Box 129)
    - The National Institute of Arts and Letters -- presidency, 1974-1975 (Box 129)
    - Objective tests, 1958-1973 (Box 129)
    - Peabody Institute, 1970-1973 (Box 130)
    - Questionnaires, 1969-1974 (Box 130)
    - Radio Programs, 1948-1971 (Box 130)
    - Television programs, 1948-1970 (Box 130)
    - Articles -- possible, 1963-1972 (Box 131)
    - Article. -- comments, 1972-1973 (Box 131)
    - Articles accepted, 1972-1973 (Box 131)
    - Articles declined, 1972-1973 (Box 131)
    - Lectures -- tentative, 1965-1973 (Box 131)
    - Lectures -- accepted, 1973 (Box 131)
    - Lectures -- declined, 1973 (Box 131)
    - The Selected Writings of John Jay Chapman. Correspondence, 1956-1971 (Box 132)
    - Follett’s Modern American Usage. Correspondence, 1958-1969 (Box 132)
    - The American University. Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 132)
  - Literary correspondence:
    - The Care and Feeding of the Mind, 1954-1969 (Box 133)
    - A Catalogue of Crime, 1969-1971 (Box 133)
    - The Energies of Art, 1955-1959 (Box 133)
    - God’s Country and Mine, 1954-1960 (Box 133)
    - The House of Intellect, 1965-1969 (Box 133)
    - Jacques Barzun on Writing, Editing, and Publishing, 1970-1971 (Box 133)
    - The Modern Researcher, (revised edition), 1960-1971 (Box 134)
    - Music in American Life, 1955-1969 (Box 134)
    - Of Human Freedom, 1961-1968 (Box 134)
    - Race: A Study in Superstition, (revised edition), 1961-1968 (Box 134)
    - Science: The Glorious Entertainment, 1965-1970 (Box 134)
    - Teacher in America, 1954-1969 (Box 134)
    - The American Scholar, 1970-1973 (Box 135)
    - The Authors Guild, Inc., 1951-1971 (Box 135)
    - Columbia Forum, 1957-1972 (Box 135)
    - Detective fiction, 1971-1972 (Box 135)
    - Life magazine -- consultant, 1949-1965 (Box 136)
    - Life magazine -- projects, 1954-1973 (Box 136)
    - Permissions, 1969-1971 (Box 136)
    - Publishing information, 1952-1972 (Box 136)
    - Translations -- plays published, 1938-1968 (Box 136)
    - Translations -- plays performed, 1950-1964 (Box 136)
    - Translations -- general correspondence, 1954-1970 (Box 136)
  - Recommendations -- friends & students: